Mss.Rec.31 Mss.Rec.31
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Na'ina (Song Sparrow) Song, 1958-08-16; 07-39; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:23; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine
    "Composed by Martha's mother. 'Song sparrow, shut up! People, talk the right way!" (Don't say mean things.) Maggy Joe later identified this song as composed by her aunt who used to live at Gulkana Airport (Dry Creek village).... Recorded by Jim McKinley (who has reputation of being best singer and dancer at Copper Center) and Martha Jackson, after they had listened to earlier recordings on this reel 8/16/58"
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Sparrows
  - Up-the-Line Song from Dawson, 1958-08-16; 07-40; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim
    "Recorded by Jim McKinley (who has reputation of being best singer and dancer at Copper Center) and Martha Jackson, after they had listened to earlier recordings on this reel 8/16/58.... Jim McKinley announced: 'We are going to sing about our two sisters (CMcC & FdeL). We're going to see them again.'"
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Han language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Sad Slow Song - "ho, hi" (Tlingit), 1958-08-16; 07-41; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim
    "Identified in 1960 as a song sung when people are resting at a potlatch.... Recorded by Jim McKinley (who has reputation of being best singer and dancer at Copper Center) and Martha Jackson, after they had listened to earlier recordings on this reel 8/16/58"
  - Tlingit Drowning Song, 1958-08-16; 07-42; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim
    "A sorry song from drowned people. (cf. Joe Goodlataw, Chitina, 1954 [APSdigrec_1094]). Chistochina people in 1960 identified this as a Chitina song, Eyak. They don't dance, but stand up and sway from side to side.... Recorded by Jim McKinley (who has reputation of being best singer and dancer at Copper Center) and Martha Jackson, after they had listened to earlier recordings on this reel 8/16/58."
  - Tlingit Dance Song, 1958-08-16; 07-43; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim
    "Recorded by Jim McKinley (who has reputation of being best singer and dancer at Copper Center) and Martha Jackson, after they had listened to earlier recordings on this reel 8/16/58"
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tlingit dance; Tlingit language
  - Tlingit Love Song, 1958-08-16; 07-44; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:19; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Martha; McClellan, Catharine; McKinley, Jim
    "(Beginning was missed.) ... 100, 200 yrs. old.... Recorded by Jim McKinley (who has reputation of being best singer and dancer at Copper Center) and Martha Jackson, after they had listened to earlier recordings on this reel 8/16/58"
  - Give me a Drink - Up-the-line, Tanacross, Song, 1958-08-28; 07-45; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:26; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy; McClellan, Catharine
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Drinking songs--Alaska; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tanacross language
  - Ahtna song, 1958-08-28; 07-46; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; McClellan, Catharine
    "Bacille recorded the song to which is the dance of the old couple and their dead baby, but his voice was so poor that he asked to have the song erased if the tape were copied or played on the Copper River."
  - Love Song, 1958-07-26; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:07; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    The words include, "Come on, come on. I think you die."
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Love songs
  - Animal Noises imitated by Douglas Billum, 1958-08-30; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:27; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    Imitation of the noises of rabbits, tree squirrels, mallards, swans, muskrats, two kinds of loons, swans, geese, groundhogs.
    Ahtena language; Animal sounds--Alaska; Copper Center (Alaska)
  - Douglas Billum's Song for his Partner, 1958-08-30; 08-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:16; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Love songs
  - Tobacco All Gone (with drum), 1958-08-30; 08-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    "Composed by Tenos Charley, a nAltcina man (not the present man of that name living in Copper Center), in 1901-02."
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Tobacco
  - Cordova, Alaska (with drum), 1958-08-30; 08-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:31; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    A song taught to the singer by a man from Juneau named Philip who came to Chitina.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Cordova (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Tlingit Song (with drum), 1958-08-30; 08-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    "An old song, learned from his grandfather."
  - Up-the-Line Dance Song (with drum), 1958-08-30; 08-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:55; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
  - Tlingit Song, "Boat Coming", 1958-08-30; 08-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:26; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    "'Boat Coming' (ref. to white men). (Tlingit words refere to yakw - boat). Learned from grandpa."
  - Andy Brown's Father's Love Song, 1958-08-30; 08-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:44; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    "Composed by Charley, nAltcina man - bai' dEna' t'a' - 'shine white father'."
  - Jesus Song, 1958-08-30; 08-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:50; Billum, Douglas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McClellan, Catharine
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Religion; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Jesus Christ--Songs and music